DAVID MORTON - 713-632-5038 - dvd.morton@gmail.com

PROFILE

Experienced developer with 17 proven years of making computers do good and useful things for humans.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Agile | Angular | ASP.NET | C# | CSS | DevOps | DI | Docker | F# | GIS | Git | HTML | Javascript | JQuery | ML | MLOps | MVC | .NET | NodeJS | PostgreSQL | Python | REST | SciKit Learn | SOLID | TDD | T-SQL | Typescript | VSTO

EXPERIENCE

Product Owner - Machine Learning Operations, Chevron, November 2019-Present

- Identified and led a team to build a workflow to deploy, monitor, and retrain ML models across the enterprise
- Worked alongside Microsoft to give feedback on their Azure Machine Learning and Cognitive Services offerings
- Consulted with Data Scientists and ML engineers to identify solutions to deployment and model management
- · Worked with architects and cloud engineers to ensure proper compliance and governance of systems

Machine Learning Engineer, Chevron, November 2019-Present

- Reorganized a development team to begin visibly showing measurable progress.
- Wrote multiple devops pipelines to ensure data science and machine learning work was deployed to production.
- · Led our team of combined data scientists and machine learning engineers towards better engineering rigor.
- Reviewed the work of other teams within the organization for deployability and long-term maintainability.
- Helped focus cloud infrastructure teams to better fill the needs of data scientists within the organization.

Lead Software Developer, Spot Traceability; May 2016-November 2019 (3 years, 5 months)

- Designed, architected, and wrote the API and web side of Spot's flagship traceability application.
- Designed and implemented a dynamic forms product used by major oil & gas clients.
- Wrote automated deployment and monitoring methodologies using Slack bots.
- Replaced a team of four external consultants in my first two months.
- Implemented over 1,200 unit tests using TDD.
- Worked remotely 100% of the time.

Associate Team Lead, JPMorgan Chase & Co.; January 2015-May 2016 (1 year, 4 months)

- Responsible for the output of an agile team of five developers.
- Ranked as "Exceeds Expectations" two years in a row.
- Selected as one of 12 employees within the company for the "Expert Engineer" program.
- Onboarded 27 independent components onto continuous integration and deployment.
- Developed small, high impact applications, deployed on over 17,000 desktops across the enterprise.
- Managed a VSTO Application with a WPF UI, and a backend on Server 2013 with 19 WCF Services.
- Turned around a struggling business unit, securing an additional \$1M to grow it.

Associate Developer, JPMorgan Chase & Co.; August 2013-January 2015 (1 year, 4 months)

- Designed and implemented a greenfield Office AddIn project.
- Led the team in story points completed, and number of lines of code written.
- Trained the team in dependency injection and TDD best practices.
- Designed a framework for 33 advanced PowerPoint charting types with custom formats.
- Defined and presented on the best practices for a proprietary DevOps system.
- Worked heavily with, and developed a testable framework around COM Interop objects.
- Integrated the front-end application with WCF services providing data from a Mongo database.

Senior Developer, LiquidFrameworks, LLC.; July 2010-August 2013 (3 years, 1 month)

- Transitioned the flagship product from a site-installed to a cloud-based product.
- Developed two iOS applications to tie into with the flagship product.
- Maintained and developed a disconnected WPF application using SQL Server Compact.
- Implemented several bits of functionality in SalesForce cloud.

- Developed integration layers for Quickbooks, MAS90, Peachtree and GreatPlains.
- Implemented NHibernate, Castle Windsor and an object proxy system for the flagship app.
- Used ProtoBuf serialization to replace SQL Server replication, speeding up sync 500-fold.
- Designed and implemented, from the ground up, an entire survey tool, along with 145 unit tests.

Senior Developer, SolArc, Inc.; March 2010-July 2010 (4 months)

- Designed and implemented a report editing component for RightAngle, a commodities trading software.
- Designed a document editing system using Windows Workflow Foundation and DevExpress tools.
- Worked with a large-scale commodities trading platform written in WinForms and C#.

Senior Consultant, Catapult Systems; August 2008-March 2010 (1 year, 7 months)

- Designed, implemented and presented on an MVVM implementation in Silverlight 3.
- Developed and ASP.NET MVC 2 application for an aviation insurance company.
- Refactored a data-driven ASP.NET project to conform to SOLID principles.
- Led various presentations on new technologies, including JQuery.
- Worked for the Houston Texans for a short period of time maintaining their internal applications.

Consultant, Catapult Systems; August 2007-August 2008 (1 year)

- Helped design and develop an ASP.NET project at a major air services provider in Houston.
- Implemented JavaScript, Jquery and AJAX into ASP.NET when AJAX was brand new.
- Implemented a WinForms application for a Florida court system using CAB and Infragistics controls.

Freelance Software Developer, Hyperactive Concepts; September 2006-June 2007 (10 months)

- Developed C#, ASP.NET and Javascript applications for clients.
- Completed an administrative back-end in T-SQL for a computer training company.

IT Applications Developer, Aaron Rents, Inc; August 2006-August 2007 (1 year)

- Integrated Lawson accounting system and Concur expense reporting system.
- Wrote an auto-dialer application with a user-friendly ASP.NET/Javascript UI.
- Integrated accounting information between Made2Manage ERP and Lawson Accounting Software.
- Worked remotely for the company during the last 6 months of my tenure.

IT Field Support, Aaron Rents, Inc; September 2005-August 2006 (11 months)

- Re-imaged store servers and workstations using Norton Ghost.
- Configured servers and workstations with DNS, DHCP, WINS, etc.
- Automated my job by creating a VBA script.
- Automated the job of my coworkers by upgrading the VBA script to VB.NET.
- Took part in an ERP implementation, including translating data from the old data source to the new.

Acquisitions Auditor, Aaron Rents, Inc; September 2004-September 2005 (1 year)

- · Led multiple acquisitions, converting data from the old POS system to the Aaron Rents POS system.
- Audited Aaron Rents store locations for compliance and risk management.
- Began efforts to automate portions of the process, including the creation of acquisitions documents.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Founder/Designer/Developer, Muxica (iPhone Application, 1000+ Units Sold); July 2012-July 2014 Founder/President, Houston F# Users Group; April 2009-December 2009

AWARDS/RECOGNITION

Microsoft MVP (C#) 2010-2011

MCTS: .NET Framework 2.0 Web Applications

EDUCATION

Texas A&M University - Bachelor's degree in psychology with a minor in philosophy - 1997-2001